# Oksana Stepanchuk

Full Stack React & Node.js Developer with 1.5 years of experience in a search of a position where I can enhance my skill set in web technologies and implement solutions to meet business needs. See my portfolio <a href="here">here</a>

Augusta, GA
(706) 220-0312
ob.stepanchuk@gmail.com
GitHub: OxiBo

<u>freecodecamp.org/oxibo</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/oksana-stepanc</u> <u>huk-59a848133/</u>

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Avenue for The Arts** — volunteer Full Stack Developer

FEB 2022 - PRESENT

**ONLINE DIRECTORY FOR ARTISTS** 

Build React/Next.js-based, interactive website for Avenue for the Arts given responsive designs via Zeplin

**Technologies:** React, Next.js, Next-Auth.js, MUI, Node.js, HTML, CSS, AWS (Lambda), MongoDB, Serverless

## Experience for 2004 - 2016 available upon request.

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

# **Cocktails App**

2021

A website that lets users find cocktail recipes (using external API), save recipes to favorites list, get information about ingredients, email recipes to the provided emails, authenticate via social network providers.

**Technologies:** Node.js, Express, Passport.js, MongoDB, React, Redux, REST, HTML, SASS

# Shop-cook App

2020

A website that lets users find recipes (using external API), modify number of servings to adjust ingredients list, create shopping lists, email the shopping lists to the provided emails, create accounts for saving recipes.

**Technologies:** Node.js, Express, Passport.js, SendGrid, MongoDB, Heroku, React, REST, HTML, Styled Components

## **Online Store**

2019

Built a website that lets users create and edit accounts, buy products, upload images, keep track of purchased products reviews, save orders list,

#### **INDUSTRY EXPOSURE**

Legal, Financial

#### **SKILLS & TOOLS**

Frontend: React, Redux, Next.js, REST, GraphQL, webpack, HTML, CSS, SASS

Backend: Microservices, Node.js, AWS Lambda, Serverless, Express, NoSQL (MongoDB), SQL

Other: Git, Material UI

**Past:** Bootstrap, Handlebars, jQuery

Tasks: Trello

## **LANGUAGES**

**Current:** JavaScript (ES5, ES6+)

### **VALUES**

Integrity, reliability, consistency, quality, attention to detail, open & direct communication, problem solving send emails functionality.

**Technologies:** Node.js, Express, Passport.js, SendGrid, Stripe, React, Redux, HTML, SASS

# **Blogging App**

2019

Built a blogging website that lets users create and edit accounts, write and post blog posts, save drafts, comment posts.

**Technologies:** Node.js, Express, Passport, MongoDB, React, Redux, HTML, SASS

## Market App

2019

Built a commercial website with functionality that lets users create accounts (authentication with JWT), sell and buy products, upload images, review products, save orders list, shopping cart and send emails functionality.

**Technologies:** React, GraphQL, Prisma, GraphQL Yoga, Stripe, HTML, Styled Components

## LogIn App

2019

Built authorization functionality for a website.

Technologies: Node.js, Express, Passport.js, MongoDB, HTML, CSS

## TwitchTV streamers

2018

Built a simple app as per FreeCodeCamp course specifications using the Twitch API to display the status of a set of Twitch Streamers. The app displays users currently streaming on Twitch.tv; lets users click the name of a streamer to be sent directly to the Free Code Camp's Twitch.tv channel; if a Twitch streamer is currently streaming, users can see additional details about what they are streaming.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, webpack, jQuery, Handlebars

#### **EDUCATION**

National Technical University of Ukraine "Igor Sikorsky Kyiv Polytechnic Institute" (NTUU KPI), Kyiv, Ukraine

Law Degree

1999 - 2004

#### **INTERESTS**

Reading books, traveling, nature, psychology